<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>McGill Biology Graduate Association</title>
    <description>Welcome to the McGill BGSA page! Here, you can find information about who we are, upcoming events, and photos of our past events as well as a compilation of handy dandy links we&#39;ve found very useful over the years. </description>
    <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://mcgillbgsa.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes!
To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 06:00:46 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/jekyll/update/2014/05/11/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/jekyll/update/2014/05/11/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BGSA Travel Grant deadline!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey BGSA! This is a reminder about the BGSA travel grant. It’s due a week from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesday, on April 9! Attached is the form you need to fill out. Here is a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reminder of the details: BGSA Travel Grant The grant is $400 and can be used&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for conferences falling between September 1st, 2013 and August 31th, 2014. If&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you’ve already attended a conference within that time frame, the grant may be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;used retroactively. For more details and policies, please see the second page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;of the application, attached here or available available on the BGSA website,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in the “Grants” section: mcgillbgsa.weebly.com To apply, please fill out the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;application and return it to me, Mary-Rose, via email (preferable) or by&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;printing it and dropping it off to me in Bellini room 232 or lab 270.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications are due April 9th, and a list of winners will be drawn randomly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on April 11th and announced that day by email. The grant will be offered to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the first person on the list (first name drawn), but in the event that this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;person declines the grant or becomes ineligible, it will be offered to the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;next person on the list, and so on until either the award is claimed or the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;award period ends. Winners must accept or decline the award by April 30th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact me if you have any questions or concerns Good luck! Mary-Rose&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 17:53:21 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2014/03/31/bgsa-travel-grant-deadline/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2014/03/31/bgsa-travel-grant-deadline/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BGSA Winter Retreat</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello BGSA and Welcome back! Here is a reminder about the Adirondacks trip in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a few weeks (look below for the info and links) Several people have signed up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;already but there are still about 10 stops left so SIGN UP SOON if you are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;still interested in coming along. This email is also a reminder for people to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bring in there deposits, we would like to have them by this Friday. So please&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bring a $20 Deposit to Mary-Rose (Bellini 266), Me (Stuart N5/5), or Claudia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(N4/6) to reserve your spot. Emails sent after today will include only the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;people who have signed up to reduce listserve spam. Thank you for your time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and sign up! Scott Check your email for the link to sign up!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 16:29:07 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2014/01/08/bgsa-winter-retreat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2014/01/08/bgsa-winter-retreat/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome back, everyone!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The BGSA is hosting a FREE Welcome back/Orientation/Karaoke night at Thompson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;House next Wednesday!! WHO: All Biology Graduate Students and Postdocs WHAT:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beer, Nachos &amp;amp; Karaoke WHEN: Wednesday January 15th from 4pm till it’s over or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomson House kicks us out. WHERE: Thomson House Basement (3650 Rue McTavish)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHY: Because the food &amp;amp; drinks are FREE and we’re lots of fun to hang out&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with! This is a great way to meet new students, catch up with old friends, and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kick off the new semester. Please bring your labmates! Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your friendly neighbourhood BGSA&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 16:27:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2014/01/08/welcome-back-everyone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2014/01/08/welcome-back-everyone/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BGSA Holiday Party: Jingle Bell-curves Rock</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey BGSA! This year’s Biology Holiday Party “Jingle Bell-curves Rock” will be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on Thursday December 5th at the Thompson House. Doors will open at 6pm, and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dinner will be served around 7pm. It’s going to be a great night filled with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;food, entertainment from your very own BGSA, and lots of dancing! Also this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;year we will be holding the first ever departmental lip syncing contest! I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;know we’re all a very competitive bunch as was demonstrated at this year’s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pumpkin carving contest so please sign up to participate (email Kiyoko with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;your name and song) and bring your A-game because I know we are :D If lip&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;syncing is not your thing, but you still want to compete in something, there&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will also be a baking contest with details on that coming soon from Dieta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring all your labmates, profs, staff and significant others!! Especially this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;year lets all really try to get our profs to come out like they used to in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;previous years! Tickets are on sale now: $15 for Faculty and Staff (and non-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McGill) $10 for Grads and Postdocs free for children They can be purchased&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from the following sellers: Stewart Bio: Claudia Wever - office N4/6; lab N4/7&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redpath Museum: Andrea Morden: office 104 (Ricciardi Lab) Bellini: Mary-Rose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bradley-Gill - office 232; lab 270 I will also be carrying some tickets around&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with me at the EEL and Organismal Seminars for the next few weeks. There’s a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;limited number of tickets so don’t wait till the last minute because they will&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sell out!!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 15:24:04 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/11/26/bgsa-holiday-party-jingle-bellcurves-rock/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/11/26/bgsa-holiday-party-jingle-bellcurves-rock/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Annual BGSA Pumpkin Carving Contest!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is the BGSA’s pleasure to announce the Annual BGSA Pumpkin Carving Contest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(applause, applause). Who? All labs (can be joined labs if not enough&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;participants….** extra points given to group with supervisor present&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When? Tuesday October 29th, 2pm Where? Lobby 4th floor of Stewart Bio (between&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North and West wings) Why? Because you’re good enough, smart enough, and dog-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on-it, people love carving pumpkins How? Bring all materials with you (knives,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;drill bits, dissecting tools, scalpels, props). Introducing…. *** IRON&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PUMPKIN!!!!*** Theme will be announced at the start of the carving, as well as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the CARVING CURVEBALL, a special item to be incorporated into your pumpkin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are allowed to bring raw materials for props, but you cannot have them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;assembled before the contest begins (one hour max for carving). You will be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;evaluated on creativity, aesthetics, incorporation of the curveball, theme and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the back-story. Dress in costumes!!! Cost: $6 Sign up by the 25th. Please give&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;money to Victor at the Redpath (103A) or to Ria Ghai at Stewart Bio - W3/5 See&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ya’ll there!…and if not, do beware… MUAHAHAHAHAHA&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 14:08:35 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/10/19/annual-bgsa-pumpkin-carving-contest/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/10/19/annual-bgsa-pumpkin-carving-contest/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome back fellow bio grad students!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey guys! The BGSA is hosting a FREE Welcome back/ orientation BBQ next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHO: All Biology graduate students and postdocs WHAT: BBQ (veggie and meat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;options), snacks and drinks (soda and other adult beverages) WHEN: Wednesday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September 4th from 4pm till it’s over or Thomson House kicks us out. WHERE:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reservoir field, the big grassy field across from Thomson House between Dr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penfield, des Pins and McTavish WHY: Because the food is FREE and we’re lots&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;of fun to hang out with! This is a great way to meet new students, catch up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with old friends, and kick off the new school year. Please bring your&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;labmates! Hope to see you there! Your friendly neighbourhood BGSA&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 22:39:09 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/08/26/welcome-back-fellow-bio-grad-students/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/08/26/welcome-back-fellow-bio-grad-students/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>End of Year BBQ!!!!!!!!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello BGSA! To cap off a great school year, the Biology Graduate Students&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Association (BGSA) is hosting a FREE BBQ on Tuesday May 14th at 4pm. There’s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;also a softball game that day at 6pm that everyone is welcome to stay for!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHO: All Biology graduate students and postdocs WHAT: BBQ (veggie and meat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;options), drinks (soda and other adult beverages) &amp;amp; softball WHEN: Tuesday May&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14th from 4-6 pm, softball from 6pm till it’s over or Thomson House kicks us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;out. WHERE: Reservoir field, the big grassy field across from Thomson House&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;between Dr Penfield, des Pins and McTavish WHY: Because the food is FREE and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we’re lots of fun to hang out with! This is a great way to meet new students,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;catch up with old friends, and kick off the summer. You don’t have to be able&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to catch, throw or hit the ball in order to play with us! Please bring your&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;labmates! Hope to see you there! Your friendly neighbourhood BGSA&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 22:06:05 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/05/10/end-of-year-bbq/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/05/10/end-of-year-bbq/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2013 CEEB Wrap-up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello CEEB Retreaters, On behalf of the 2013 organizing committee I would like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to thank all the speakers, moderators and participants for contributing to an&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;outstanding CEEB retreat. A number of you requested the slides from the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;workshops and we have make them available on BGSA Speaker Deck account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/bgsa&quot;&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/bgsa&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carly Zitter also live tweeted Workshop #2. If you missed the workshop or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;want to relive it you can find the transcript as on Storify here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://storify.com/cziter/graphical-design-for-publications-and-your-researc&quot;&gt;http://storify.com/cziter/graphical-design-for-publications-and-your-researc&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you at next years retreat!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS These workshops are great for the whole department, not just CEEB!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 18:02:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/04/17/2013-ceeb-wrapup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/04/17/2013-ceeb-wrapup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BGSA Welcome Back Event</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;BGSA,  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure what to do this Thursday? Please refer to the attached decision map&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the BGSA officers have created for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All models suggest you attend the 2013 BGSA Welcome Back event this Thursday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at Thomson House from 5-7pm. The BGSA will be providing snacks, beverages and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the First Annual Masterpiece crafts competition. Where we give you a picture&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.artinfo.com/artintheair/files/2012/10/restoredfresco.jpg&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or [this](http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/f/f4/The_Scream.jpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/220px-The_Scream.jpg) and you have to recreate it with a team consisting of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;any combination of lab, friends, enemies from popsicle sticks, glue and some&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pipe cleaners with prizes for the best interpretation as judged by a panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you have to bring is a good time and your lab mates.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come catch up with me, other graduate students, faculty and meet new people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you Thursday,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monica&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BGSA President&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Thursday Decision Map](http://www.scribd.com/doc/120505398/Thursday-Decision-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Map) by&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 13:45:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/01/15/bgsa-welcome-back-event/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mcgillbgsa.com/archive/2013/01/15/bgsa-welcome-back-event/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
